Fletcher Forum of World Affairs UP149
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, 1976 -- 2019; UP149.001; 1.75 Linear Feet; 1060 Digital Object(s)
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, 2009; UP149.001.00069 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Protecting Latin America's Gains through the Current Financial Crisis, 2009; UP149.001.00069.00012; Cox, Pamela; Pamela Cox, the World Bank's Vice President for Latin America and the Caribbean Region, outlines the impact of the financial crisis on Latin American economies. She highlights how the loss of available credit and the collapse of commodity prices may have dramatic long-term consequences and jeopardize development gains throughout the region. To safeguard development and accelerate Latin America's economic recovery, Dr. Cox proposes five priorities for action for governments and multilateral institutions.
    - Disaster Risk and its Reduction: Who Is Responsible?, 2009; UP149.001.00069.00013; Wahlstrom, Margareta; The UN Secretary-General's Special Representative for Disaster Risk Reduction, Margareta Wahlstr6m explores the configuration of disaster risk globally and explains why "extreme weather and geological outbursts ... need not lead to disasters." If effective action is not taken, disaster risk will steadily grow and may result in catastrophes that erase development gains and destabilize countries around the globe. International agreements such as the Hyogo Framework for Action and the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change can help governments manage and reduce their country's disaster risk in a changing climate. Moreover, efforts to systematically link disaster risk reduction and climate change adaptation represent a policy breakthrough that must be reinforced through implementation.
    - Reassessing the Traditional Skill-Transfer Paradigm: The Example of Rwanda, 2009; UP149.001.00069.00014; Whitlock, Reid E.; Rwanda expert Reid Whitlock discusses skill transfer in and out of Rwanda during the last decade. A close examination of these processes in Rwanda reveals a diverse range of skill-transfer trends that collectively undermine the conventional wisdom, which maintains that developing countries import skills from developed countries and seldom export them. Whitlock shows that, in fact, Rwanda is a successful importer of skills from other developing countries, such as Sri Lanka, Kenya, and the Democratic Republic of Congo, and an exporter of skills to Burundi.
    - Saviors and Survivors, 2009; UP149.001.00069.00015; Mamdani, Mahmood, 1946-; Book Review
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, 2010; UP149.001.00070
    34, 1
    - Table of Contents, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00001
    - Ending Sexual Violence in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00002; Breton-Le Goff, Gaelle; While local and international NGOs seek to address the crisis facing the Democratic Republic of the Congo, perpetrators of human rights crimes are still largely able to avoid being brought to justice. Gaelle Breton-Le Goff, Lecturer in International Human Rights Law at the University of Quebec, outlines the driving forces behind the massive sexual violence and proposes key social, legal, and diplomatic approaches for international policymakers.
    - Traversing the Persian Gauntlet: U.S. Naval Projection and the Strait of Hormuz, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00003; Gresh, Geoffrey F.; Geoffrey Gresh, a PhD candidate at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, explores the geopolitical significance of the Straits of Hormuz- the narrow waterway connecting the Persian Gulf with the Arabian Sea-and its implications for U.S. naval policy in the region. Despite potential threats from Iran and al-Qaeda, he argues that a robust U.S. naval presence is not necessary to protect the Straits and that U.S. national security interests in the Gulf can be met with a much smaller naval deployment and increased cooperation with regional allies.
    - The Northern Mind in American Diplomacy, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00004; Henrikson, Alan K.; Twenty years ago, Professor Alan K. Henrikson, Director of Diplomatic Studies at The Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, published an article in The Fletcher Forum examining the impact of the "Southern Mind" on Secretary of State's Dean Rusk's foreign policy. In this follow-up, Henrikson turns his attention to another American statesman, George Kennan, and a competing "Northern" influence on U.S. foreign relations.
    - The Kurdish Issue in Iraq: A View from Baghdad at the Close of the Maliki Premiership, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00005; Visser, Reidar; As violence in Iraq has subsided since 2007, the "Kurdish issue" has reemerged as one of the greatest threats to future stability in Iraq. Reidar Visser, Research Fellow at the Norwegian Institute of International Affairs, traces the history of Kurdish claims for autonomy and Iraqi federalism and argues that the greatest potential for solving the conflict requires returning to the more limited Kurdish aims from before the 2003 invasion.
    - Reflections on U.S. Policy in Africa, 2001-2009, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00006; Frazier, Jendayi E.; Jendayi Frazer was the U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs from 2005 to 2009. In this retrospective of U.S.-African relations during the Bush Administration, she notes that more wars were ended, more successful elections were held, more sustained growth was achieved, and more lives were saved from pandemic diseases than during any previous U.S. presidency. She points to a combination of greater engagement by the United States and a commitment to supporting uniquely African ideas solutions as having helped produce these remarkable outcomes.
    - Leadership in Counterinsurgency, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00007; Moyar, Mark; Counterinsurgency analysts are largely divided between the "hearts and minds" and "enemy-centric" schools of thought. Both trends neglect a core determinant of any counterinsurgency campaign's effectiveness: leadership traits. Mark Moyar, Professor of National Security Affairs at the U.S. Marine Corps University, argues that policymakers should focus on ten core leadership attributes, ranging from initiative to organization, in evaluating counterinsurgency cases. This leader-centric approach may unveil critical insight on how to maximize success against insurgencies in such complex situations as the Afghanistan war.
    - After the War: Nation-building from FDR to George W. Bush, 2010; UP149.001.00070.00008; Dobbins, James; Poole, Michael A.; Long, Austin; Runkle, Benjamin; Book Review
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, 2010; UP149.001.00071
    34, 2
    - Table of Contents, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00001
    - Fashioning a Realistic Strategy for the Twenty-First Century, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00002; Gelb, Leslie H.; "Smart" power and "soft" power have become buzzwords to describe how a state can exert influence short of using force. The Fletcher Forum interviewed Leslie Gelb, president emeritus of the Council on Foreign Relations, to discuss the nature of power and its importance to U.S. grand strategy in the twenty-first century. Gelb points out that while the essential meaning of power has not changed, power today is measured far more by the size of a nation's economy than the size of its military force.
    - Engaging the Muslim World, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00003; Abbas, Hassan; In June 2009, U.S. President Barack Obama delivered an address in Cairo, Egypt, calling for a "new beginning" between the United States and the Muslim world. Approaching the first anniversary of the speech, The Fletcher Forum sat down with Columbia University Professor Hassan Abbas to discuss if, and how, relations between the United States and the Muslim world have changed during the Obama Presidency.
    - A Golden Moment: Applying Iraq's Hard Lessons to Strengthen the U.S. Approach to Stabilization and Reconstruction Operations, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00004; Bowen, Jr., Stuart W.; In response to the perceived dysfunction of U.S. civil-military coordination in Iraq, Special Inspector General for Iraq Reconstruction Stuart Bowen proposes developing a United States Office for Contingency Operations (USOCO). He outlines staffing and responsibilities for this permanent office that would improve the ability of the U.S. government to assist in reconstruction activities around the world.
    - The Hamas-Fatah Conflict: Shallow but Wide, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00005; Brown, Nathan J.; Ever since the Palestinian Authority violently split into Hamas and Fatah camps in 2007, Gaza and the West Bank have followed markedly different trajectories. The West Bank has experienced relative peace and prosperity while Gaza has suffered under diplomatic isolation and an Israeli-imposed blockade. Nathan Brown, professor of political science and international affairs at George Washington University, elucidates the traditional differences and growing similarities between Hamas and Fatah, including their methods of governing, monopolization of violence, and the nature of the political parties themselves.
    - The Bioterror Pipeline: Big Pharma, Patent Expirations, and New Challenges to Global Security, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00006; Finlay, Brian; Brian Finlay, senior associate at the Henry L. Stimson Center, argues that although new biotechnologies have yielded tremendous benefits for humanity, they remain a major potential threat to global security. Increasingly, the fundamental challenge of the biotech revolution is to ensure that technologies with a legitimate use in the civilian economy are neither inhibited by overly invasive legal restrictions, nor diverted for nefarious use as bioweapons.
    - Reaping the Whirlwind: Pakistani Counterinsurgency Campaigns, 2004-2010, UP149.001.00071.00007; Breyman, Steve; Salman, Aneel; As the United States and NATO redouble their efforts to restore stability to Afghanistan, the importance of Pakistan's role in the conflict has become increasingly clear. Pakistan's willingness to confront insurgent groups, however, has been inconsistent at best. In this article, the Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute's Steve Breyman and Aneel Salman compare Pakistani counterinsurgency strategy under the presidencies of Pervez Musharraf and Asif Ali Zardari.
    - Ending the Exploitation of Migrant Workers in the Gulf, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00008; Auwal, Mohammad A.; While the Arab Gulf states have received considerable attention for their tremendous natural-resource wealth, far less focus has been placed on the system of migrant labor that underpins their economic growth. In this revealing article, Mohammad Auwal, professor of communication studies at California State University in Los Angeles, uses first-hand accounts to shed light on the plight of migrant laborers working in the Gulf.
    - Yemen and the United States: Conflicting Priorities, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00009; Rugh, William A.; Yemen has once again become a key counterterrorism priority. William Rugh, former U.S. ambassador to Yemen, argues that U.S. officials must strive to align American objectives with those of Yemen's President, Ali Abdullah Salih.
    - To Tackle C0 2, Start with H20: How Latin America's Water Problems Could Affect Climate Change Negotiations, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00010; Moreno, Luis Alberto; Despite its economic reliance on water resources, Latin America is especially vulnerable to disturbances in water supplies resulting from global climate change. President of the Inter-American Development Bank Luis Alberto Moreno therefore sees a unique opportunity to re-engage Latin American policymakers in global climate negotiations.
    - From a Global Burden to an Engine of Growth: Reframing Climate Policy After Copenhagen, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00011; Brookes, Tom; After a prolonged build-up, the international climate summit in Copenhagen disappointed many in failing to conclude a legally binding, international treaty. Tom Brookes, managing director of the Energy Strategy Centre, explores the reasons why the conference fell short of expectations and where global climate policy may go from here.
    - A Millennium of Byzantine Power, 2010; UP149.001.00071.00012; Luttwak, Edward E.; Book Review
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2011; UP149.001135 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    35, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2011; UP149.001136 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    35, 2
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2012; UP149.001137 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    36, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2012; UP149.001138 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    36, 2
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2013; UP149.001139 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    37, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2013; UP149.001140 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    37, 2
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Special Edition 2013; UP149.001141 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    37, 3
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2014; UP149.001142 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    38, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2014; UP149.001143 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    38, 2
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2015; UP149.001144 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    39, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2015; UP149.001145 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    39, 2
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2016; UP149.001146 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    40, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2016; UP149.001147 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    40, 2
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2017; UP149.001148 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    41, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2018; UP149.001149 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    42, 2
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Winter 2019; UP149.001150 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    43, 1
  - The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer 2019; UP149.001151 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    43, 2